Okay, so in this video then, we are going
to discuss the scope baseline,
another very important project artifact.
Now remember, there are four baselines.
I mean, there's three main baselines and
then collectively they
make another baseline.
So we have the scope baseline, the
schedule baseline, and the cost baseline.
And the three of those put
together make up the fourth
one called the performance
measurement baseline.
And those are some of the components that
make up the project management plan.
So in this section then, we are discussing
one of them called the scope baseline.
And remember, what is a baseline?
It is the approved version of the plan,
approved by the sponsor, the project
manager and other key stakeholders,
other key project stakeholders.
Once the appropriate
parties have approved and
signed off, then that plan
has now been baseline.
So in this case then, we talk about the
scope.
This is the approved version of the scope.
Now the scope baseline contains three
items.
And these are the three items.
Make sure you know what these three items
are.
Make sure you know them.
Because again, you could be asked some
direct questions on that.
They could literally ask you what the
scope baseline made up of.
and it's made up of the work breakdown
structure, the WBS.
It's made up of the WBS dictionary,
right?
The work breakdown structure dictionary.
It's also made up of the scope statement.
It's made up of these three items.
Okay, so let's talk about each of these.
So at WBS and work breakdown
structure, right, we have
a separate video covering
the work breakdown structure.
So remember the work
breakdown structure is a graphical
hierarchy of all the work that
needs to be done on the project.
It's a hierarchical depiction of the
project scope.
This is what the project is about.
It's a decomposition,
decomposition of the entire project,
going to decomposing your
project down to the work package.
Now, when you look at the work breakdown
structure though, you've got all these
different boxes there, it's showing all
the different boxes and in all the
different areas that we need to focus on
on the project.
However, there's no real details about the
work, the actual work that's involved in,
you know, for example, creating the work
package.
For example, it doesn't document who is
going to be working on it, on each work
package, as in what team is going to be
responsible.
It doesn't have any
detailed description about
all the activities that
need to be done, right?
Work breakdown structure doesn't contain
any activities.
It doesn't show you a cost estimate,
right?
How much is this work package going to
cost or the schedule, any milestones.
It doesn't document any assumptions or
constraints.
It doesn't show you any interdependencies
between work package.
Is one work package dependent on another
work package starting?
It doesn't show you any of that detail,
any of those detailed information,
right, in the WBS.
That information is in what's known as the
dictionary, the work
breakdown structure dictionary.
So the WBS.
Yes, dictionary contains all of that
information and all of those details, right?
So, work breakdown structure component
details, right, all the details regarding
the work package, right, the description
of the work, what work actually is
involved, team responsible, cost
estimates, milestones, schedules,
any assumptions and constraints, also then
interdependencies between
one work package and another.
All of that is documented here in the
dictionary.
And then the other component then is a
scope statement.
Again, we have a separate video on the
scope statement and a scope statement
then, a detailed description of the work,
detailed description of the deliverable,
the work needed to complete those
deliverables.
So basically then it contains the product
scope and the project scope.
Okay, so the scope baseline
then contains these three
items, the WBS, the WBS
dictionary and the scope statement.